CLAUDIO CAMBA | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

<u>claudiocamba1@gmail.com</u> ❖ 07791 778 960 ❖ London, UK <u>claudiocamba.com</u> ❖ <u>github.com/claudiocamba</u> ❖ <u>linkedin.com/in/claudiocamba</u>

PROFILE

Creative problem solver with over four years experience as a Front End Developer, where I honed my skills in agile development and delivery-focused workflow. In addition to my experience in frontend and backend development my responsibilities included Quality Assurance, A/B testing, help desk support, writing documentation, training and presenting. I seek challenging opportunities in software development to further leverage my technical and analytical skills to produce creative solutions.

SKILLS

Frontend: React, React Native, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, SASS, HTML, Bootstrap, Material UI

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Supabase, Relational Databases, Complex SQL Queries

Test | Quality Assurance: Jest.js, Supertest, BrowserStack, Test-Driven Development (TDD)

Tools: Git, npm, Github, Bitbucket, Webpack, Netlify, Vite, Confluence, Jira, Figma, Photoshop, Excalidraw, Invision,

Adobe XD, Sketch, Adobe Target, Dynamic Yield, Visual Website Optimizer (VWO), Optimizely

Concepts | Models: Pair Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Functional Programming, Model View Controller (MVC), Version Control, Document Object Model (DOM), CI/CD, Minimal Viable Product (MVP)

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer - Northcoders Bootcamp

Nov. 2023 – Mar. 2024

- Developed Android application using React Native & Supabase
- Built full-stack CRUD applications using modern frontend and backend technologies
- Created pixel perfect user interface using React, Javascript, CSS, SASS and Bootstrap
- Created RESTful API endpoints utilising Node, Express and PostgreSQL
- Conducted code reviews, pull requests to features are quality-assured

Front End Developer - Dentsu International

Aug. 2022 - Mar. 2023

- Worked on high profile client websites to improve customer journey and experience
- Built A/B, MVT and Recommendation (Machine Learning) tests to increase conversion
- Inspected and provided feedback to peer test builds to guarantee quality consistency
- Developed reusable and dynamic components utilising front-end technologies

Front End Developer - Cheil Worldwide | Samsung

Jan. 2019 - May. 2022

- Created A/B tests, personalising consumer experience to improve conversion and revenue
- Optimised websites based on designs, using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Adobe Target
- Performed QA and debug inspections to ensure tracked elements data is correct
- Responsible for Optimisation implementation during the Samsung Flagship launches
- Identified brief feasibilities for strategists, to ensure that the project is completed on time
- Managed Jira Service Desk to support markets with queries regarding test builds
- Supported multiple markets by creating in-depth tutorials and code generators
- Trained and onboarded Samsung markets on Adobe Target, Confluence and Jira

Junior Front End Developer – Evokeu

Sep. 2018 - Jan. 2019

- Transformed designs into functional user Interface using HTML, CSS & ¡Query
- Liaised with clients to determine their requirements and follow up with regular updates
- Collaborated with the design team to complete projects within the given timeframe

EDUCATION

University of Westminster - Bachelor of Arts, Animation

2010 - 2013

Produced films utilising numerous concepts in animation and visual design

CERTIFICATIONS & INTERESTS

- Certifications: Software Engineering, Front End Development, Advanced CSS3 & HTML5, WEB Authoring
- Interests: Painting, Drawing, Exercising, Movies and Boxing